ultracart.com 2019-01-24

# Privacy Policy

_Effective 05-24-2018_

UltraCart has never and will never sell your data. UltraCart has never and will never give your data to third party unless explicitly instructed by you for the operation of your online store, such as a fulfillment house, payment processor, or your email marketer.

* * *

Your privacy is important to us. We provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way we collect and use your information to better protect your privacy. This privacy policy is available on our homepage.

By using any of UltraCart’s services, or interacting with a merchant using UltraCart’s services, you are agreeing to the terms of this Privacy Policy and, as applicable, the UltraCart Terms of Service.

* * *

#### Information from merchants:

This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the UltraCart website. On some pages, you may submit information about your company. The type of information collected on these pages are:

  * Name
  * Address
  * Email address
  * Phone number
  * Credit/Debit Card Information
  * Product Information
  * Pricing Information
  * Your website name
  * Additional store configuration

* * *

#### The way we use merchant information:

We use the information you provide about your company only to provide the UltraCart services that power your online store. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to provide the expected service.

We use return email addresses to answer the email we receive. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties. We use name and merchant account during chat help to access account information and provide assistance. Any information collected during a support chat session is retained solely to make improvements to our platform and customer service.

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our website and to share with advertisers. For example, we may tell an advertiser that X number of individuals visited a certain area on our website, or that Y number of men and Z number of women filled out our registration form., but we would not disclose anything that could be used to identify those individuals. The information collected is anonymous.

We may also share your information in the following circumstances:

  * to prevent, investigate, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Service or any other agreement related to the Services, or as otherwise required by law.
  * to help us conduct marketing and/or advertising campaigns.
  * to conform to legal requirements, or to respond to lawful court orders, subpoenas, warrants, or other requests by public authorities (including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements).

We retain merchant personal information throughout their relationship with UltraCart. When a merchant cancels their service, they are given a choice to delete their personal data after 60 days or retain their data indefinitely. Many merchants are seasonal and desire to retain their store and settings for intermittent use. Other merchants wish to leave their store intact in case they wish to return to UltraCart at a later date.

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses. For a complete list of privacy issues please read section 8 of the Terms and Conditions of service before signing up for the service.

* * *

#### Information from merchant's customers

On some pages, your customers can order products, make requests, and register to receive materials. The types of personal information collected at these pages are:

  * Name
  * Address
  * Email address
  * Phone number
  * Credit/Debit Card Information
  * (etc.)

On some pages, customers can submit information about other people. For example, if a customer orders a gift online and want it sent directly to the recipient, the customer will need to submit the recipient's address. In this circumstance, the types of personal information collected are:

  * Name
  * Address
  * Phone Number
  * (etc.)

We use the information customers provide about themselves when placing an order only to complete that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order.

We use the information customer's provide about someone else when placing an order only to facilitate shipment of the product and to confirm delivery. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order.

We use some of the personal information you provide us to conduct some level of automated decision-making -- for example, we use certain personal information to help us screen accounts for risk or fraud concerns.

We allow merchants to use opt in emails collected during their customer’s shopping experience to do follow-up marketing to their customers. We do not share their email addresses with other merchants or third parties.

We may also share customer information in the following circumstances:

  * to prevent, investigate, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Service or any other agreement related to the Services, or as otherwise required by law.
  * If a merchant directs us to transfer this information (for example, if they enable a third party app that accesses customer personal information).
  * to conform to legal requirements, or to respond to lawful court orders, subpoenas, warrants, or other requests by public authorities (including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements).

We may collect anonymous information related to UltraCart themes to improve those themes. This includes devices, operating systems, browser types, screen resolutions, and any errors generated during a customer’s experience. This information cannot be used to identify a customer and is used solely by UltraCart for product improvement.

Our merchants may use customer tracking products such as inspectlet.com for the purpose of improving their websites hosted by UltraCart. UltraCart requires merchants to abide by UltraCart Terms and Conditions when collecting such data, including regional laws such as the EU GDPR 2018.

* * *

#### Our commitment to data security

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online as defined by the Payment Card Industry (PCI-DSS Version 3.1) and regional laws where applicable.

We perform annual audits conducted by third party auditing firms to ensure our compliance with PCI-DSS Level 1, which is the highest level of compliance available.

No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your personal information.

* * *

#### Our commitment to children's privacy:

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13.

* * *

#### How you can access or correct your information

You may access all your company information that we collect online and maintain according to our UltraCart privacy policy. We use this procedure to safeguard your information.

* * *

#### How To Contact Us

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please call us at 209-383-9870 or send us an email at [support@ultracart.com](mailto:support@ultracart.com).
